## **MDASHRAFUR RAHMAN**



01611-777750

ashraf-rahman



Dakshin Khan, Uttara



aashraf.rahman@gmail.com



### **SUMMARY**

Experienced professional with 9+ years of experience in trade marketing, sales & distribution. Played several key role along with territory and regional leadership role to drive business. Posses hands on experience on distributor management, Route to market, leading sales force and agency field force in a MN FMCG company. Led several key projects like distributor changeover, dealer market takeover, and brand augmentation plan. Completed and earned several online certification on Digital marketing courses. Key strength- Leading team, Strategic planning and execution, sales forecasting, analytical skills, developing new talents

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Regional Sales Lead



**Partex Star Group** 

11/2020 – Present Chattogram & Sylhet

- Grew regional business by 46% in H1- 2021 vs 2020 amidst all the challenges
- Appointed an exclusive dealer in Cox's bazar
- Reduced market credit by 1.3 pp in Q2 vs Q1 2021
- Leading 2 regions with 12 team members

#### Freelancer

#### Independent



1/2019 - 10/2020

### Territory Officer (G33)

#### **British American Tobacco**



3/2014 - 10/2018 Pabna

- **Distributor Changeover in Pabna**: played a pivotal role in distributor changeover in Pabna, 2<sup>nd</sup> biggest distributor in the Rajshahi region
- Prepared 22 candidate profile
- Coordinated with cross functional team
- Formulated contingency to avert any sales loss
- Route to market: prepared "0" based route plan to improve expand outlets and distribution efficiency
  - 2.5k outlets increased
  - 39 distribution vehicle increased and capacity improved
  - 3 new distribution points established
- Prism roll out: implemented automated sales system replacing manual hand written-memo system
- Managed agency and led agency FF i.e BR, CM

### Territory Officer (G32)



**British American Tobacco** 

12/2010 - 2/2014 Sylhet/Laxmipur

- Streamlined sub-distributor market in Laxmipur replacing one sub-distributor in Raipur
- **Project Falcon**: Prepared and implemented brand augmentation plan in addition to central plan in the Area
- Streamlined dealer market with exclusive distribution

#### Executive

#### **Aamra Group Of Companies**



12/2007 - 12/2008

Dhaka

#### **RECOGNITION**

#### YES Your Enterprising Spirit

- Received 8 YES Tier-2 award
- Received Tier-3 award for highest volume growth
- Received Tier-1 award for managing price compliance in the territory
- Received "Outstanding" rating for 2017 performance

#### TRAINING/CERTIFICATION

#### **Fundamentals of Digital Marketing**

Online certification course on Digital marketing by Google through online

#### **Web Analytics**

Online certification course on web analytics by Linkedin learning

#### **Effective Business Communication**

2 days of training arranged by BATB which was facilitated by Grow n Excel

#### **Positive**

Training on effective sales management

### **SKILLS**

- Sales and distribution || Trade Marketing
- Leading teams
- Distributor/Dealer management
- Negotiation || Analytical skills
- Digital marketing || Social media marketing

### PROJECTS AND INITIATIVE



### **Project Kairos**



Distribution Changeover in Pabna

• The project was completed within 22 WDs with a very small team of 3 people

.....

### **Project Seahawk**



2018 Pabna, Ishwardi

Outlet expansion and distribution efficiency

• Implemented "0" based route plan for outlet expansion and distribution efficiency in Pabna and ishwardi territory

### **Project Falcon**



2015 Feni Area

Brand Augmentation Plan

 Prepared and implemented brand augmentation plan in addition to central plan to launch a new brand

### **Project Transformer**



2012 Sylhet

Brand migration plan

• Successfully implemented Bristol to Derby migration plan in the territory

### Project Phoenix



2018 Dhaka

Press box renovation at Chittagong Stadium

 Led the project of renovating press box of Ctg cricket stadium sponsored by Aamra Group

.....

### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelors in Business Administration



Brac University 2003 - 2007 GPA

**3.02**/4.0

# Higher Secondary certificate

Rajuk College Uttara

Result

1<sup>st</sup> Division

2002

Secondary school

Secondary schoo certificate

Result

1<sup>st</sup> Division

Banani Bidyaniketan



1999